Sudha Chaudhry

sudhachaudhry1999@gmail.com +91 7249903777 www.linkedin.com/in/sudha2512chaudhry https://github.com/sudha0125chaudhry https://sudha0125chaudhry.github.io/ https://www.hackerrank.com/sudhachaudhry25

Objective

I am an undergraduate in B. Tech. ECE with specialization in Robotics and IoT. I am a progressive learner, effective communicator, team player and have a keen interest in expanding my knowledge about various technologies in the IoT domain through various career opportunities.

Work Experience

Content Creator (Jun 2021 - Sept 2021)

Medguru

Authored academic content for NEET aspirants.

Content Writer (Jun 2021 - Jul 2021) Harivali NGO

Authored technical and non-technical content for the organisation's blog and help promote their digital presence.

Link: https://eduindex.org/author/sudhachaudhry19991185/

Curriculum Writer (Jun 2021 - Jul 2021)

Team Everest NGO

Craft English Grammar worksheets for government school students.

Teaching Assistant (Aug 2020 - Sep 2020) VSD Public School

Successfully taught "Basics of HTML" to 7^{th} standard students over an online platform.

Content Writer (Apr 2020 - Jul 2020)

Vetwe Media

Authored content for their company's blogs – Gamer Rewind and Finance Rewind on topics such as current internet trends, entertainment, technology, finance, and games.

Link: https://gamerrewind.com/author/sudha/

Publication

"A Survey on Long Wide Area Network (LoRaWAN)," A Journal of Advanced Research in Networking and Communication Engineering, Dec 2019

Link: http://thejournalshouse.com/index.php/adr-networking-communication-eng/article/view/179

Education

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering (Jun 2018 - Present)

NIIT University, Neemrana, Rajasthan Specialization – Robotics and IoT

Senior Secondary (2017)

VSD Public School, Bijnor, Uttar Pradesh Board – CBSE

Secondary (2015)

VSD Public School, Bijnor, Uttar Pradesh Board – CBSE

Positions of Responsibility

- Course Project Mentor | NIIT University
- Student Mentor | Resonance 2019 | NIIT University
- Coordinator | Instils Photography Club | Resonance 2019 | NIIT University
- Head Girl | VSD Public School
- Member | TECH FEST Organising Committee | VSD Public School
- Member | SAPTRANG Organising Committee | VSD Public School
- Compère | SAPTRANG | VSD Public School

Technical Skills



Projects

Application of IoT in Smart Navigation (Jan 2021 - May 2021)

GitHub Link:

 $https://github.com/sudha0125 chaudhry/RnD-IOT-Navigation \\ \textbf{YouTube Link:}$

https://youtu.be/907mNmVgeys

• PID Balance+Ball (Jan 2021 - May 2021)

YouTube Link:

https://youtu.be/sqBt5FlZrY4

• Line Follower using PID (Jan 2021 - May 2021)

YouTube Link:

https://youtu.be/bE6gIcFbiE4

• Echo Generation and Cancellation (Mar 2020 – Jun 2020)

GitHub Link:

https://github.com/sudha 0125 chaudhry/Echo-Generation- and Cancellation

YouTube Link:

https://youtu.be/ZRo_wcow6j8

• Hydro Infinity (May 2020 - Jun 2020)

GitHub Link:

https://github.com/sudha0125chaudhry/Hydro-Infinity

YouTube Link:

https://youtu.be/KGz8PGdq8Is

• Plant Monitoring System (Nov 2019 - Dec 2019)

GitHub Link

https://github.com/sudha0125chaudhry/Plant-Monitoring-System YouTube Link:

https://youtu.be/NouAV1APVbg

• Hand Gestures Controlled Computer (Jan 2019 - Apr 2019)

GitHub Link:

https://github.com/sudha0125chaudhry/Hand-Gesture-Controlled-Computer

YouTube Link:

https://youtu.be/o-yrBs5L19o

Achievements

- 30 days Google Cloud Program | Qwiklabs (Dec 2020)
- HackNU 2.0 | NIIT University (Jun 2020)
- Certificate of Publication | Advanced Research Publications (Feb 2020)
- Letter of Appreciation | Human Resource Development | Government of India (Jul 2015)

Volunteer Experience

- Volunteer | Kitchen Garden | Team Everest NGO
- Problem Analyst | Unnat Bharat Abhiyan | NIIT University
- Student Mentor | Community Connect | NIIT University
- Fundraising Assistant | HelpAge India | VSD Public School
- Fundraiser | Caring Souls Foundation | VSD Public School